<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Nándor</title>
    <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Nándor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 16:53:47 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arch Packages</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/arch-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 20:10:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/arch-packages/</guid>
      <description>Editors &amp;amp; Tools p gdisk partition manager Development p hugo static website generator p vimpager less replacement Browsers &amp;amp; Players p task taskwarrior p firefox web browser p cmus terminal-based music player p vlc or mpv video player p thunar or nemo graphical file manager p gthumb image viewer y tor-browser p virtualbox Fun p cmatrix cool animation p figlet cool text p lolcat cool colors p neofetch mandatory for Arch Hardware &amp;amp; Desktop p slock screen locker p firejail sandboxer p ufw uncomplicated firewall Install Scripts Requires Javascript</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archinstall</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/archinstall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 15:14:28 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/archinstall/</guid>
      <description>Arch Linux is a Linux distro that&amp;rsquo;s relatively hard to install. While guided installers do exist, part of an Arch user&amp;rsquo;s pride comes from going through the process manually. It&amp;rsquo;s actually not difficult at all - running a list on commands in the right order with occasional decisionmaking woven in - but it is a great learning opportunity.
This guide is based on my personal notes. Parts not relevant to me, such as a non-English keyboard layout it omitted because I never needed it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 15:10:49 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/git/</guid>
      <description>What is Git? made by Linus Torvalds to manage the Linux kernel distributed, non-linear workflows free/open-source network/server not required Graphical Clients frontend to git commands provide some helpful visualizations I recommend learning the commands themselves Sourcetree Github Desktop GitKraken Git GUI My notes contain Markdown/HTML tables in this format. This is to make it easy to export them. See J2A.
Front Hotkey Command Notes Perskey Start git repo git init Commits What&amp;rsquo;s a commit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 15:10:47 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/vim/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 15:10:43 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/bash/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
