<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Nándor</title>
    <link>http://nandor.ml/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Nándor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 16:30:54 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://nandor.ml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wout</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/apps/wout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 10:48:30 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/apps/wout/</guid>
      <description>Wout Wout Get ready to take your fitness journey to the next level with Wout! Our workout tracking app is designed to help you reach your fitness goals and stay motivated along the way.
&amp;#xf3ab; Download From google play &amp;#xf17b; Download From f-droid &amp;#xf09b; Download From github Easy to Use Our app boasts a modern and user-friendly interface that makes tracking your workouts a breeze. No need to spend hours figuring out how to use the app – Wout has a simple design that lets you log your sets, reps, and weights in no time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Pro Tips</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/life-pro-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 08:18:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/blog/life-pro-tips/</guid>
      <description>Food If you&amp;rsquo;re not particularly good at cooking, or won&amp;rsquo;t have much time to do so, get yourself a slow cooker. Put a small cup filled with water in the microwave when reheating pizza or pasta. Using an electric kettle will always be more efficient than a stove. Rice is cheap and filling. Peanuts have lots of protein. Financial Make a bank account as soon as you legally can. Be the sole owner of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Apps</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/android-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 04:19:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/blog/android-apps/</guid>
      <description>In my last blog post, I described the installation process of my new phone. I am extremely happy with both the device and LineageOS.
However, LineageOS only ships a few bare essential apps, such as Calendar or Clock. They do not have many features either.
This is a good thing. I intentionally chose a non-bloated ROM so that I can configure it to my liking.
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll detail all the choice I made in terms of apps to install.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Perfect Phone</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/my-perfect-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 02:07:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/blog/my-perfect-phone/</guid>
      <description>I try to not rely on my phone too much. I don&amp;rsquo;t think everything should be an app, and I&amp;rsquo;d rather not have daddy Google track every step I take. There&amp;rsquo;s some irony to it - Android development is literally my profession - but maybe that&amp;rsquo;s exactly why I try to separate work from personal use.
As a Linux user, I&amp;rsquo;m used to a customizable system made of open-source components. Android is definitely better than its main competitor, iOS in this regard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ich Habe Meine Daten Gesichert</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/ich-habe-meine-daten-gesichert/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 02:44:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/blog/ich-habe-meine-daten-gesichert/</guid>
      <description>Dieser Artikel ist auf Deutch. Ich bin kein Muttersprachler, also bitte verzeih mir bitte meine Fehler. Das ist meine Art, zu üben!
Was Ich Will Um den Kontext zu verdeutlichen: Hier geht es um die Sicherung von Dateien unter Arch Linux.
Mein Laptop hat eine 2TB SSD (wovon 1TB wichtig ist).
Ich habe auch eine externe Festplatte mit 1 TB, die ich für Sicherungskopien verwenden möchte.
Die 3-2-1-Regel Es gibt einen beliebten Ratschlag, wenn es um Dateisicherungen geht:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xargs</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/xargs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 23:34:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/xargs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction source allows for piping to the command arguments essentially converts stdin to command line call as with all stdin programs, if you don&amp;rsquo;t pipe another command into it, input is read from the terminal command1 | xargs command2 particularly useful for calling programs with the output of dmenu Separation by default, xargs collects all of stdin and executes the command once this can be changed to run the command every X lines or space-separated words a custom delimiter can also be given Front Hotkey Command Notes Perskey Run xargs command after every line of input xargs -L 1 figlet Run xargs command after every word of input xargs -n 1 figlet Run xargs command separated by &amp;lsquo;w&amp;rsquo; xargs -n 1 -d w figlet Delimiter Options xargs -t to also print the command being ran xargs -r to only run if stdin is not empty xargs -p to prompt Substitution if the command is not specified, it&amp;rsquo;s echo the argument(s) are appended at the end by default -I implies -L1 Front Hotkey Command Notes Perskey Run xargs using substitution for the argument xargs -I {} figlet a {} b Run multiple commands in an xargs call xargs -I {} sh -c &amp;ldquo;figlet {} &amp;amp;&amp;amp; echo {}&amp;rdquo; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riding the Git-Wave</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/ai-stuff/riding-the-git-wave/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 13:57:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/blog/ai-stuff/riding-the-git-wave/</guid>
      <description>Write my a power metal song in the style and with the patterns of the band Dragonforce. Make it about the version control system Git. Praise its usefulness and reference its features and subcommands.
ChatGPT
Verse 1:
With the power of Git, we&amp;rsquo;ll conquer all
Never lose our code, never let it fall
Merging and branching, it&amp;rsquo;s all so neat
Push and pull, with Git, can&amp;rsquo;t be beat
Chorus:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Into Programming - Beginner&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/get-into-programming-beginner-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 20:10:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/blog/get-into-programming-beginner-guide/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Programming (also known as coding or development) can be a creative hobby, a lucrative career, or both.
The main skill required for a programmer is problem solving. &amp;ldquo;I want to achieve X, what can I do to achieve X?&amp;rdquo;
It&amp;rsquo;s also important to be adaptable, open to learning new things. The field is ever-evolving, and there&amp;rsquo;s always something new to learn.
Finally, if you don&amp;rsquo;t intend to work on solo projects, efficient communication with teammates is crucial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cron</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/cron/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 22:12:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/cron/</guid>
      <description>Introduction cronjob, crontab source source if a cronjob is supposed to execute, but the system is turned off, the cronjob will be skipped % signs in cronjob definitions need to be escaped as \% see logs: sudo cat /var/log/cron Installation There are multiple implementations. Example using Cronie and Arch:
sudo pacman -S cronie sudo systemctl enable --now cronie Jobs Front Hotkey Command Notes Perskey Edit crontabs crontab -e Show crontabs crontab -l Run crontab as another user crontab -u Times .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjectives</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/german/adjectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 11:48:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/german/adjectives/</guid>
      <description> Articles Only Nominativ Akkusativ Dativ Genitiv der Mann den Mann dem Mann des Mannes ein Mann einen Mann einem Mann eines Mannes das Haus ←das Haus ↑dem Haus ↑des Hauses ein Haus ←ein Haus ↑einem Haus ↑eines Hauses die Frau ←die Frau der Frau ←der Frau eine Frau ←eine Frau einer Frau ←einer Frau die(pl) Kinder ←die Kinder den Kindern ↑der Kinder keine Kinder ←keine Kinder keinen Kindern ↑keiner Kinder Adjectives Nominativ Akkusativ Dativ Genitiv der kleine Mann den kleinen Mann dem kleinen Mann des kleinen Mannes ein kleiner Mann einen kleinen Mann einem kleinen Mann eines kleinen Mannes kleiner Mann kleinen Mann kleinem Mann kleinen Mannes das kleine Haus ←das kleine Haus ↑dem kleinen Haus ↑des kleinen Hauses ein kleines Haus ←ein kleines Haus ↑einem kleinen Haus ↑eines kleinen Hauses kleines Haus ←kleines Haus ↑kleinem Haus ↑kleinen Hauses die kleine Frau ←die kleine Frau der kleinen Frau ←der kleinen Frau eine kleine Frau ←eine kleine Frau einer kleinen Frau ←einer kleinen Frau kleine Frau ←kleine Frau kleiner Frau ←kleiner Frau die(pl) kleinen Kinder ←die kleinen Kinder den kleinen Kindern ↑der kleinen Kinder keine kleinen Kinder ←keine kleinen Kinder keinen kleinen Kindern ↑keiner kleinen Kinder kleine Kinder ←kleine Kinder kleinen Kindern ↑kleiner Kinder </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Skyrim and Doom Are Awesome</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/why-skyrim-and-doom-are-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 18:24:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/blog/why-skyrim-and-doom-are-awesome/</guid>
      <description>Skyrim Skyrim is a medieval fantasy RPG set in the world of Elder Scrolls. The planet is called Nirn, the continent Tamriel, and the country, well, Skyrim.
The player can freely explore the open world right after the tutorial area. She&amp;rsquo;s encouraged to fight bandits, save people, learn magic, kill dragons, ride dragons, and influence the political landscape.
Skyrim is widely praised for how much it lets the player customize her Dragonborn, be it a Nord fighter wielding a greatsword, the oh-so-prevalent stealth archer Khajiit, or a mage who challenges herself by using anything but the Destruction school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Keyboard Layouts</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/custom-keyboard-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 17:32:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/blog/custom-keyboard-layouts/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re using a PC or laptop keyboard, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance it comes with the EN (US) keyboard layout. That&amp;rsquo;s the letters of the English alphabet, along with special symbols like ;:&#39;&amp;quot;[](). This is a great layout for general use as well as programming.
What this layout lacks is the special letters non-English languages use. Hungarian uses óöőúüűí, German öüäß, and Romanian îăâșț, along with their capitalized versions.
To type these letters, the typical solution is to change the keyboard layout to the language&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joke</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/joke/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 17:50:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/joke/</guid>
      <description> A nap vicce </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Your Website for Free</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/how-to-create-your-website-for-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 11:37:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/blog/how-to-create-your-website-for-free/</guid>
      <description>There can be many good reasons to create a website. It can act as a professional portfolio, inform visitors about an event, host a comic series, or any of the other endless possibilities.
Though much of the modern web is bloated with tracking and cookie popups, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be this way. There is still a place for simple, functional websites.
This blog post will detail how I created my own website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch Packages</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/arch-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 20:10:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/arch-packages/</guid>
      <description>Editors &amp;amp; Tools p gdisk partition manager Development p hugo static website generator p vimpager less replacement Browsers &amp;amp; Players p task taskwarrior p firefox web browser p cmus terminal-based music player p vlc or mpv video player p thunar or nemo graphical file manager p gthumb image viewer y tor-browser p virtualbox Fun p cmatrix cool animation p figlet cool text p lolcat cool colors p neofetch mandatory for Arch Hardware &amp;amp; Desktop p slock screen locker p firejail sandboxer p ufw uncomplicated firewall Install Scripts Requires Javascript</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LiveData</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/livedata/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 11:25:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/livedata/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Binding</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/data-binding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 10:35:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/data-binding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>build.gradle</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/build-gradle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 10:31:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/build-gradle/</guid>
      <description>Kotlin-kapt Documentation compiler plugin that supports annotation processing example use cases are Dagger2 and Data Bindig </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrofit</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/retrofit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 09:49:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/retrofit/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kotlin</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/kotlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 17:39:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/kotlin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RxJava</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/rxjava/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 17:39:35 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/rxjava/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Room</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/room/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 17:39:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/room/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviews</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 17:35:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/interviews/</guid>
      <description>SOLID Single Responsibility Principle Open/Closed Principle Liskov’s Substitution Principle Interface Segregation Principle Dependency Inversion Principle </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hilt</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/hilt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 17:35:50 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/hilt/</guid>
      <description> library made by Google dependency injection makes testing easier usually done in the constructor built on top of Dagger2 Links Documentation CodingWithMitch&amp;rsquo;s course and project CodingWithMitch&amp;rsquo;s video </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dagger</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/dagger/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 17:35:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/android/dagger/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archinstall</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/archinstall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 15:14:28 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/archinstall/</guid>
      <description>Arch Linux is a Linux distro that&amp;rsquo;s relatively hard to install. While guided installers do exist, part of an Arch user&amp;rsquo;s pride comes from going through the process manually. It&amp;rsquo;s actually not difficult at all - running a list on commands in the right order with occasional decisionmaking woven in - but it is a great learning opportunity.
This guide is based on my personal notes. Parts not relevant to me, such as a non-English keyboard layout it omitted because I never needed it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 15:10:49 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/git/</guid>
      <description>What is Git? made by Linus Torvalds to manage the Linux kernel distributed, non-linear workflows free/open-source network/server not required Graphical Clients frontend to git commands provide some helpful visualizations I recommend learning the commands themselves Sourcetree Github Desktop GitKraken Git GUI My notes contain Markdown/HTML tables in this format. This is to make it easy to export them. See J2A.
Front Hotkey Command Notes Perskey Start git repo git init Commits asd &amp;ndash;asd&amp;ndash; ddd</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 15:10:47 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/vim/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 15:10:43 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/cheatsheets/linux/bash/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Commit</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/initial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 17:30:12 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/blog/initial/</guid>
      <description>Welcome H2 here H3 here Hello, welcome to my website!
As you can probably tell, ++this++ is my first blog-style post.
I&amp;rsquo;m using this page as a way of testing how certain elements look.
I&amp;rsquo;m using this page as a way of testing how certain elements look.
I&amp;rsquo;m using this page as a way of testing how certain elements look.
I&amp;rsquo;m using this page as a way of testing how certain elements look.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
