<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Nándor</title>
    <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Nándor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 16:53:47 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://nandor.ml/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why Skyrim and Doom Are Awesome</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/why-skyrim-and-doom-are-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 18:24:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/blog/why-skyrim-and-doom-are-awesome/</guid>
      <description>Skyrim Skyrim is a medieval fantasy RPG set in the world of Elder Scrolls. The planet is called Nirn, the continent Tamriel, and the country, well, Skyrim.
The player can freely explore the open world right after the tutorial area. She&amp;rsquo;s encouraged to fight bandits, save people, learn magic, kill dragons, ride dragons, and influence the political landscape.
Skyrim is widely praised for how much it lets the player customize her Dragonborn, be it a Nord fighter wielding a greatsword, the oh-so-prevalent stealth archer Khajiit, or a mage who challenges herself by using anything but the Destruction school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Keyboard Layouts</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/custom-keyboard-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 17:32:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/blog/custom-keyboard-layouts/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re using a PC or laptop keyboard, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance it comes with the EN (US) keyboard layout. That&amp;rsquo;s the letters of the English alphabet, along with special symbols like ;:&#39;&amp;quot;[](). This is a great layout for general use as well as programming.
What this layout lacks is the special letters non-English languages use. Hungarian uses óöőúüűí, German öüäß, and Romanian îăâșț, along with their capitalized versions.
To type these letters, the typical solution is to change the keyboard layout to the language&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Commit</title>
      <link>http://nandor.ml/blog/initial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 17:30:12 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nandor.ml/blog/initial/</guid>
      <description>Welcome H2 here H3 here Hello, welcome to my website!
As you can probably tell, ++this++ is my first blog-style post.
I&amp;rsquo;m using this page as a way of testing how certain elements look.
I&amp;rsquo;m using this page as a way of testing how certain elements look.
I&amp;rsquo;m using this page as a way of testing how certain elements look.
I&amp;rsquo;m using this page as a way of testing how certain elements look.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
